<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop | JIHYUN</title>
    <link>https://Jihyuncindyhur.github.io/tag/workshop/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Jihyuncindyhur.github.io/tag/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Workshop</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 23:19:37 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Jihyuncindyhur.github.io/images/icon_huba1290056a9aa64b0b71a1bf18bd3dc1_31701_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Workshop</title>
      <link>https://Jihyuncindyhur.github.io/tag/workshop/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got accepted to attend ABCD workshop in Portland, OR!</title>
      <link>https://Jihyuncindyhur.github.io/post/abcdworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 23:19:37 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Jihyuncindyhur.github.io/post/abcdworkshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent an amazing week at the Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development workshop held in Portland, Oregon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop focused on reproducible neuroimaing methods, predictive modeling approaches, and clincial menal health outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the workshop, I had an opportunity to learn connectotyping, a novel approach to characterize resting-state functional connectivity, from Dr. Oscar Miranda-Dominguez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by this concept, I suggested an open hackathon idea and formed a group of 5 to apply connectotyping and partial least squares regression (PLSR) to the ABCD and ABIDE data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fit the connectotyping data to PLSR to predict fluid intelligence scores in a data-driven approach. Interestingly, the preliminary result showed that the connectotyping data with the somatosensory cortex performed better than the null data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we were not testing any specific hypotheses, the project had not been developed further. However, I still learned so much from this opportunity! Hope I can attend the next one soon :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
